So now that we have all the information
in this spreadsheet, we're going
to perform some calculations.
Now in this video, I'm just going to
demonstrate how you can use the basic
mathematical functions, such as addition,
subtraction, multiplication, and minus.
In the next video, we will demonstrate
how you can use specific functions within
Excel to sort of automate these tasks,
make it more straightforward and simpler.
But in this short video, I'm just going
to demonstrate how you can simply add,
divide, multiply and subtract information.
So Excel uses cell references.
As you can see, in this one
here I've selected cell E14.
I could select any cell.
I could select a cell over here and still
perform a calculation on that information
that would be displayed here, but I'm
just going to select this one here, E14.
And what I want to do is I'm just going
to add two of the figures together.
So what I need to do is I need to tell
Excel that what's in this cell is going
to equal the addition of two other cells.
So the first thing I need to do is type
in the equal sign and then select the
first cell, which is that one there.
And as you can see, it's got a blue
line - it is moving around the cell,
which shows that it's been selected.
And then I simply need
to tell it what to do.
So it could be addition,
multiplication, division or subtraction.
So I'm just going to add that to that.
And I'm then going to add the next cell
in that column and again, the next cell.
And then the next cell.
So if I press enter now that will give
me the total for all of the March sales.
So that is quite straightforward way
of adding a group of cells together.
And I'll just delete that.
And it may be that you wish
to multiply some information.
So I'm going to select the March sales
again, I'm just going to type into
this cell equals and it's going to be
that cell and the star symbol is the
multiplication symbol on the keyboard.
And I'm going to multiply
it by that, press enter.
And that gives you the multiplication.
If you double click on a cell, you can
see the formula that is in that cell.
But in addition to that, if you
just highlight the cell, you will
be able to see in the formula bar,
the exact formula or technique that
you've used to calculate information.
So I'll just escape from that.
And similarly, I'm going to do equals and
I'm going to select that cell there, and
I'm going to divide that cell and use the
division symbol by that cell, press enter.
And that gives me the figure
there and exactly the same
would apply for subtraction.
As long as you put the equal signs
in there, Excel will know that you
are going to carry out a calculation.
So in the next video, what we'll do is
we'll look at how Excel can automate that
process and the functions that you can use
to create the figures that you require.